Erik Hoffman

erikhoffmancs.com

Address: Aurora, Ontario | Home Phone#: 1-289-383-4992 | Email: erik hoffman@outlook.com

WORK OBJECTIVE

To find a position that allows me to use my strong background in computer science and software engineering skills to work on innovative technologies and modern applications.

In combination with these core credentials I would apply my well developed team working abilities gleaned from both my work and school experience in software development life cycles. I believe that a foundation in critical thinking and perfect communication with your team go hand-in-hand in creating successful projects.

QUALIFICATIONS

- → Multiple years of programming in C, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, Javascript, EcmaScript, Typescript, C++
- → Strong skills in frontend frameworks; Angular2, AngularJS and React as well as some jsp
- → Strong skills in NodeJS and Java servers
- → Intermediate skills in Amazon Web Services and Microsoft Azure
- → Focus on test-driven development to ensure business logic remains untouched by new code
- → Linux/Windows command line, bash scripts to automate backups and deployments
- → Git experience in a professional multi-environment setting
- → Knowledge of Jenkins, Jira, Bitbucket, Confluence, Trello
- → Created technical documents and deployment instructions as well as tutorials for coworkers

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH

Guelph, ON

Bachelor of Computing Honours (B.Comp)

Computer Science Major, Mathematics Minor

Fall 2012 - Fall 2016

Notable Courses Completed: Data Structures, Networking and Web Development, Operating Systems, Discrete Mathematics, Combinatorics and Graph Theory, Algorithms, Security (RSA and prime mathematics), Microprocessors and Assembly Language, Theory of Computation, Databases, Artificial Intelligence, File Storage Structures and Data Retrieval.

BRADFORD DISTRICT HIGH SCHOOL

Bradford, ON

Fall 2007 - June 2011

Took Computer Science courses starting in grade 10, Ontario Scholar all 4 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

CANADIAN IMPERIAL BANK OF COMMERCE (CIBC)

Toronto, ON

Intermediate Applications Developer

January 2017 - Present

- → Placed onto a multi-million dollar budget, client-facing project in an agile environment, developed during two week sprints
- ightarrow Used current technologies such as AngularJS, NodeJS, KarmaJS, Jira, Bitbucket, Jenkins
- → Development in NodeJS involved creating and maintaining RESTful APIs to interface between legacy java servers and the Angular frontend
- → Simultaneously worked on and maintained legacy Java applications including working with server code written using SOAP
- ightarrow Wrote deployment scripts in Jenkins and wrote technical documents on how to maintain environments

UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH

Guelph, ON

Teaching Assistant for Introduction to Computing

September 2016 - December 2016

- → Assist students with learning basics of applications: Word, Excel, Powerpoint and Access as well as teaching some Javascript
- → Conducted office hours, answered student questions at any time and graded assignments